[
  {
    "question": "Which atom has the greatest number of unpaired electrons?",
    "options": [
      "P",
      "V",
      "Fe",
      "Cu"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Fe",
    "topic": "Chem311",
    "id": "Chem311-zue8"
  },
  {
    "question": "Samples of four different substances are analysed using time of flight mass spectrometry. In each case, the samples are ionised to form ions with a single positive charge. The ions are accelerated to the same kinetic energy. Which sample gives ions with the shortest time of flight?",
    "options": [
      "A sample of ^45^Sc that is ionised using electron impact ionisation.",
      "A sample of C~3~H~8~ that is ionised using electrospray ionisation.",
      "A sample of CH~3~CH~2~OH that is ionised using electrospray ionisation.",
      "A sample of CO~2~ that is ionised using electron impact ionisation."
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "A sample of CO~2~ that is ionised using electron impact ionisation.",
    "topic": "Chem311",
    "id": "Chem311-xeg9"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which element has the highest third ionisation energy?",
    "options": [
      "Li",
      "Be",
      "K",
      "Ca"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "Be",
    "topic": "Chem311",
    "id": "Chem311-ipee"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the percentage atom economy for the formation of sodium nitrate in the reaction between sodium carbonate and nitric acid?  \n\nNa~2~CO~3~ + 2 HNO~3~ &rarr; 2 NaNO~3~ + H~2~O + CO~2~",
    "options": [
      "36.6%",
      "50.3%",
      "57.8%",
      "73.3%"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "73.3%",
    "topic": "Chem312",
    "id": "Chem312-0r8z"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which involves the formation of a dative covalent bond?",
    "options": [
      "PCl~3~ + Cl~2~ &rarr; PCl~5~",
      "Na^+^ + H^-^ &rarr; NaH",
      "Mg + Cl~2~ &rarr; MgCl~2~",
      "BH~3~ + H^-^ &rarr; BH~4~^-^"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "BH~3~ + H^-^ &rarr; BH~4~^-^",
    "topic": "Chem313",
    "id": "Chem313-w9t6"
  },
  {
    "question": "The table shows some results from a titration. Titration:  \n  \n| | Rough | Titre 1 | Titre 2 | Titre 3|  \n|----------------------|-------|---------|---------|---------|  \n|Initial reading / cm^3^ | 0.00  |  11.30  |  0.00   |  8.55 |  \n|Final reading / cm^3^   | 26.85 |  37.20  |  26.20  |  34.55 |  \n|Titre volume / cm^3^    | 26.85 |  25.90  |  26.20  |  26.00 |  \n  \nWhat is the correct mean titre?",
    "options": [
      "25.95 cm^3^",
      "26.03 cm^3^",
      "26.10 cm^3^",
      "26.24 cm^3^"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "26.03 cm^3^",
    "topic": "Chem312",
    "id": "Chem312-3300"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which element has the lowest melting point?",
    "options": [
      "Na",
      "Mg",
      "K",
      "Ca"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "K",
    "topic": "Chem313",
    "id": "Chem313-6xm6"
  },
  {
    "question": "Values of the ionic product of water (K~w~) at different temperatures are given.  \nK~w~ = 6.40 &times; 10^-15^ mol^2^ dm^-6^ at 18&deg;C  \nK~w~ = 1.00 &times; 10^-14^ mol^2^ dm^-6^ at 25&deg;C  \n\nWhich statement is correct?",
    "options": [
      "The concentration of hydroxide ions in water at 18&deg;C is 8.00 &times; 10^-8^ mol dm^-3^",
      "The dissociation of water into ions is an exothermic process.",
      "The pH of water is the same at 25&deg;C and at 18&deg;C",
      "Water becomes less acidic as the temperature is raised."
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "The dissociation of water into ions is an exothermic process.",
    "topic": "Chem3112",
    "id": "Chem3112-ooig"
  },
  {
    "question": "Use this information to answer the question below:  \n\nC(s) + O~2~(g) &rarr; CO~2~(g) &Delta;H = −393.5 kJ mol^-1^  \n\nH~2~(g) + &frac12; O~2~(g) &rarr; H~2~O(l) &Delta;H = −285.8 kJ mol^-1^  \n\n3 C(s) + 4 H~2~(g) &rarr; C~3~H~8~(g) &Delta;H = −104.0 kJ mol^-1^  \n\n4 C(s) + 5 H~2~(g) &rarr; C~4~H~10~(g) &Delta;H = −125.2 kJ mol^-1^  \n\nWhat is the enthalpy of combustion, in kJ mol^-1^, of propane?",
    "options": [
      "−211.7",
      "−419.7",
      "−2220",
      "−2878"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "−2220",
    "topic": "Chem314",
    "id": "Chem314-5wev"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement explains why the rate of a reaction increases when a catalyst is added to a reaction mixture at a constant temperature?",
    "options": [
      "The collision frequency increases because there is an increase in the activation energy.",
      "The collision frequency increases because there is an increase in the mean energy of the particles.",
      "The proportion of successful collisions increases because there is a decrease in the activation energy.",
      "The proportion of successful collisions increases because there is an increase in the mean energy of the particles."
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "The proportion of successful collisions increases because there is a decrease in the activation energy.",
    "topic": "Chem315",
    "id": "Chem315-9kgc"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which statement about the industrial production of ethanol from ethene at 300&deg;C is correct?  \n\nC~2~H~4~(g) + H~2~O(g) &#8652; C~2~H~5~OH(g)  &Delta;H = –46 kJ mol^-1^",
    "options": [
      "An increase in pressure decreases the equilibrium yield of ethanol.",
      "An increase in pressure increases the value of Kc",
      "An increase in temperature increases the equilibrium yield of ethanol.",
      "An increase in temperature decreases the value of Kc"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "An increase in temperature decreases the value of Kc",
    "topic": "Chem316",
    "id": "Chem316-wu6j"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which equation represents the process that occurs when the standard enthalpy of atomisation of iodine is measured?",
    "options": [
      "&frac12;I~2~(s) &rarr; I(g)",
      "I~2~(s) &rarr; 2I(g)",
      "&frac12;I~2~(g) &rarr; I(g)",
      "I~2~(g) &rarr; 2I(g)"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "&frac12;I~2~(s) &rarr; I(g)",
    "topic": "Chem318",
    "id": "Chem318-fojf"
  },
  {
    "question": "The results of an investigation of the reaction between P and Q are shown in this table.  \n| Experiment | Initial [P] / mol dm^-3^ | Initial [Q] / mol dm^-3^ | Initial rate / mol dm^-3^ s⁻¹|  \n|------------|------------------------|------------------------|----------------------------|  \n|1 | 0.200 | 0.500 | 0.400  \n|2 | 0.600 | To be calculated | 0.800 |  \n  \nThe rate equation is: rate = $k [P] [Q]^2$  \nWhat is the initial concentration of Q in experiment 2?",
    "options": [
      "0.167",
      "0.333",
      "0.408",
      "0.612"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "0.408",
    "topic": "Chem319",
    "id": "Chem319-7aav"
  },
  {
    "question": "A cell with EMF = +2.15 V is made from two electrodes.  \nThe half-equations for the two electrodes are shown.  \nPositive electrode:  \n\nPbO~2~(s) + 3 H^+^(aq) + HSO~4~^-^(aq) + 2 e^-^ &rarr; PbSO~4~(s) + 2 H~2~O(l)  \n\nNegative electrode:  \n\nPbSO~4~(s) + H^+^(aq) + 2 e^-^ &rarr; Pb(s) + HSO₄^-^(aq)  E&deg; = –0.46 V  \n\nWhat is the standard electrode potential of the PbO~2~ / PbSO~4~ electrode?",
    "options": [
      "–2.61 V",
      "–1.69 V",
      "+1.69 V",
      "+2.61 V"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "+1.69 V",
    "topic": "Chem3111",
    "id": "Chem3111-3ja2"
  },
  {
    "question": "The equation for the complete combustion of butane is:  \n\nC₄H₁₀ + 6.5 O~2~ &rarr; 4 CO~2~ + 5 H~2~O\n\nWhat is the mole fraction of butane in a mixture of butane and oxygen with the minimum amount of oxygen needed for complete combustion?",
    "options": [
      "0.133",
      "0.153",
      "0.167",
      "0.200"
    ],
    "correctAnswer": "0.133",
    "topic": "Chem3110",
    "id": "Chem3110-pvb0"
  }
]